Juan Orozco

919-793-3740 JuanOrozco.com JuanTheDesigner@gmail.com

Personal Summary

My passion for the web stems from a wonder and zeal of inventing and exploring. Originally focused on Industrial Design, I pivoted and turned to the web. Finding a world ripe with new exploration opportunities, I dove in with the aims of learning as much as possible and benefiting the overall state of the web.

Through my diverse work experiences over the past ten years, I have honed my skills as a web developer; first as a server-side craftsman. I then moved on to front-end development and, now, focus on User Experience and mentoring.

Web development is still in a formative state, which encourages exploration and community. Within this dynamic, I continue to learn and participate in all aspects of web application product development with an emphasis on mentoring colleagues.

Objective

I am at my best when creating innovative, inspiring, challenging, and fun applications within a respectful and creative company, alongside talented and friendly team members.

Skills

Languages, Data Formats

CoffeeScript	CSS	4D	GIT
HTML	JavaScript	JSON	Lua
Markdown	MSSQL	MySQL	Node.js
Pascal (Delphi)	PHP	Ruby	SVN
XML	•	. ,	'

Frameworks

CANJS	DHTMLx	jQuery	jQuery UI
Mustache	PHPUnit	Pure CSS	qUnit
RequireJS	Selenium	Underscore	

Services & APIs

Bamboo Evernote	Bower Firebase	Confluence FishEve	Dropbox Ghost
Grunt	Jira	Mozilla Persona	OAuth
Trello	WordPress		

Experience

Application Engineer at Knowledge Sharing Systems

Raleigh, NC || Nov. 2012 - Current

PHP, 4D, Node.js, Selenium, PHPUnit, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Introduced versioning using Subversion and GIT.
- Spearheaded automated builds and integration testing with Selenium and PHPUnit using Bamboo.
- Improved core application MVC structure by creating a basic API and a more scalable MVC structure.
- Learned the 4D scripting language and API.
- General application engineering creating and modifying modules for the flagship application and SaaS applications.
- Conducted research with end users.
- User Experience work included user research and interface design.

Lead Web Developer at Maximum Processing

Garner, NC || Jun. 2011 - Nov. 2012

Pascal/Delphi, MSSQL, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Selenium

- Lead project developer for multiple clients; managed milestones and issue tracking.
- Designed and built various portable and dynamic modules for core system that reduced developer time and bug tickets.
- · Initiated and increased awareness of development best practices through training, company Wiki, and Code Snippet repository.
- Moved code base from in-house versioning system to more robust Subversion.

Web Developer at City of Fayetteville

Fayetteville, NC | Jan. 2011 - Jun. 2011

ASP.NET, VB.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery

- Project lead on internal application for city employees that built dynamic forms.
- Responsible for websites including main landing site, the Police Department, and the Fire Department.
- Built custom responsive CSS and JavaScript frameworks for use on all city owned websites.
- Designed and implemented various interfaces for geographic data using GIS data and Google Maps API.
- User experience advising and mentoring with application developers and GIS developers.
- Utilized ADA-compliance and accessibility techniques.

Application and Experience Engineer at End Game Studio

Raleigh, NC || Jul. 2005 - Current

Front end technologies, Bower and Grunt for automation and builds, PHP and WordPress for backend and CMS.

- Full stack developer for private and commercial clients.
- UX Engineer User research, interface designer, copy editor.
- Maintain web host server and WordPress CMS.
- Developed small web applications and tools to increase personal productivity and work-flow.
- Training on CMS, social media, and other tools

Technology Support Technician at College of Management, NCSU Raleigh, NC || Oct. 2007 - Oct. 2008

- Supported classroom technology, student and faculty computing, and special event administration.
- Coordinated technology resources for lectures and presentations given by CEO's and other VIP's in 1500 seat auditorium.
- Deployed, supported, and repaired all faculty and student computing resources. Supervised volunteer students.
- Created documentation, scheduled training and recording sessions for video recording classroom.
- Consulted on design for upgrades and modification for instructional technology.
- Learned the Crestron Simple+ programming language; refactored and improved interfaces college-wide.

Education

ITT Technical Institute

Oxnard, CA, Fall 2004

Electronics Technology, Programming

Ventura College

Ventura, CA, Fall 1999 - Summer 2004

Electrical Engineering, Architectural Drafting, Programming